Verwood, Dorset, South West England paul.e.bennett@icloud.com +44 (0)7825 618 444 (Mobile)

## IT Consultant

Accomplished and technically refined consultant with broad experience in providing business expertise that identified cost saving opportunities, capacity and performance improvements within financial and banking institutions.

Proven track of success in technical and business constancy, capacity management, performance management system enhancements, and cost reduction. Efficient communicator, able to transform strategic ideas and vision into reality through close communication with management teams and stakeholders. Collaborative communicator, focused on building everlasting relationship and synergy across business lines and clients to drive positive change.

## Highlights of Expertise

- System Launch & Implementation
- Performance Administration
- Strategic Planning & Execution
- Capacity Management
- Software Testing & Analysis
- Communication skills

- Quality Assurance & Control
- System Optimisation
- Drafting & Reporting
- Process Improvements
- Issues & Conflicts Resolutions
- Team Collaborator

# Career Experience

## Euroclear SA/NV, Brussels, Belgium

Supported in the evaluation process of capacity related issues and delivered appropriate resolutions through producing Ad-hoc reporting system that enhanced the productivity of the organisation.

#### CAPACITY MANAGEMENT INFRASTRUCTURE CONSULTANT (Contract Sep 2009 to Oct 2017)

Formulate and implement effective plans to increase the capacity/performance of the current infrastructure. Deliver executive-level leadership for CA capacity management, EPV z/OS Plus, Mxg, SAS software, and administration of capacity management team that ensured that business requirements were met. Display exceptional expertise for accurate migration of CA-Mics, Mxg and Sas code to CA-Capacity Management (Capman) and EPV z/OS plus software packages.

- Administration of (CA-Capacity Management, CA-Mics, EPV product suite, Sas and Mxg) to facilitate capacity management team infrastructure that optimised IT infrastructures, tools and described ITIL framework.
- Designed, Created, Analysed, Implemented and maintained data collectors (written in Sas code) to ensure the storage of required data for IBM Tivoli Data Warehouse, including (Aix, Esx, Linux, Solaris, and Windows) Capacity management team's data.
- Streamlined processes for developing and testing software upgrades to (CA-Mics, SAS, MXG and EPV) that enhanced the operational efficiency and characteristics improvement of the operating system(s).
- Work on Project related tasks, attend related meetings, take ownership of any actions relating to our Team.

# Cpt Global Limited, Richmond, Surrey, England

Drafted and submitted detailed opportunities excel spreadsheets after the utilisation of tuning opportunities to Tesco's assignment to display the volume of saved CPU resource.

## PERFORMANCE TUNING TECHNICAL CONSULTANT (Contract Oct 2008 to Nov 2008)

- Designed opportunities/cost savings Excel pivot tables, spreadsheets, and graphs for Cpt global and Tesco's management.
- Direct efforts towards extracting daily SMF data through use of MXG and SAS to develop 'JOB' Csv files that loaded into opportunities/cost savings Excel spreadsheets to show CPU resource savings on tuned jobs.

## ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Chase Manhattan Bank / JPMorgan Chase / IBM Uk, Bournemouth, Dorset, England IT Capacity Planning & Performance Management Specialist

(Permanent Sep 2000 to Jul 2008)

#### CAREER NOTE

Chase Manhattan Bank / JPMorgan Chase, Bournemouth, Dorset, England Senior Operations Analyst

(Permanent Jan 1993 to Sep 2000)

Chase Manhattan Bank, Bournemouth, Dorset, England Operations Analyst

(Permanent Sep 1989 to Dec 1992)

Kingston and Sutton Joint Computer Centre, Worcester Park, Surrey, England

Shift Leader, Senior Operator, Operator, Trainee Operator

(Permanent Sep 1979 to Sep 1989)

# **Education & Credentials**

Code Institute Diploma in Software Development (Online) Ongoing 2018

City and Guilds 747, Merton Technical College, Merton, Greater London, England

#### COMPUTER PROGRAMMING AND INFORMATION PROCESSING (All sections passed with distinction)

Courses and Workshops: The Ultimate Excel Programmers Course 2018 | Excel Data Analysis with Excel Pivot Table 2018 | The Complete Web Developer Course 2.0 2018 | Learn SQL Reporting Services 2018 | SQL Server Essentials 2017 | Perl Programming: Fundamentals Course 2016 | CA Capacity Management Course 2016 | EPV z/OS+ Course 2016 | ITIL (Metron) Capacity Management Foundation course 2014 | HDA Influencing Skills Workshop 2009 | IBM Tivoli Omegamon Administrators course 2008 | IBM Tivoli Omegamon XE and DE introductory Workshop 2008 | HDA Interview Preparation Workshop 2008 | CMG (Computer Measurement Group) in San Diego 2007 | Capacitas IBM Mainframe Capacity & Performance Management, 2006 | UKCMG Masterclass Capacity Management Seminar 2006 | OS/390 Workloads 2005 | OS/390 Workload Manager 2001 | SAS Further Data Manipulation & Efficiency Techniques 2001

Technical Skills: Software Ag Adabas & Natural | Seasoft \$Avrs Output Management | BMC Mainview / Visualizer | Computer Associates MICS | Computer Associates Capacity Management | Computer Associates Ca7 Scheduling | Cics | IBM Data Facility / Data Set Services (DFDSS) | IBM Data Facility Hierarchical Storage Management (DFHSM) | Docutext | Fileaid | Ftp | IBM Job Control Language (Jcl & Utilities) | Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL) | Microsoft Office Access | Microsoft Office Excel (Including Macro's & Vba) | Microsoft Office PowerPoint | Microsoft Office Project | Microsoft Office Word | Mxg | Mvs / Z/os Operating System | Network Data Mover (Ndm) | IBM Omegamon Monitor | Php | Perl | Projects IN Controlled Environments (Prince2) | IBM Tso/e Rexx Programming Language | IBM Resource Management Facility (Rmf)1,2 3 & Spreadsheet Reporter | Sas (V9.2) & (V9.4) | Sas Macros (V9.2) & (V9.4) | Sas Graph (V6) | Sql | IBM System Management Facility (Smf) | Strobe | Data Integration Software Syncsort | ASG Tmon Monitor | IBM Tivoli Omegamon DE & XE | IBM Tivoli Datawarehouse (TDW) | IBM Tso / Ispf | Microsoft Visio | IBM Virtual Storage Access Method (Vsam) | Microsoft Windows | IBM Workload Manager (WLM) | Computer Associates Xcom

**Technology:** IBM Aix | IBM | Series | Linux | Liniux on z/OS | IBM P Series | IBM Z Series | EMC,IBM,Storagetek Dasd | Ficon | IBM Hydra (Ts7700) & Vts | San | Unix | Windows